Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): In the civil service deputizing billionaire oligarchs using the DOJ to settle scores now getting into a yelling match the Ukrainian president Donald Trump appears to be Putinizing the American presidency at a very rapid pace. Joining me now is Senator Richard Blumenthal at Democratic Connecticut part of a bipartisan group of senators who met with the Ukrainian president earlier today before Donald Trump kicked him out. I want to ask you about that meeting but first just on that story I was talking about
which
has
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): not kind of blown up into a scandal in the way the Eric Adams scandal
Speaker 2: was, but has very similar contours insofar as the kind of huge red flag of the line attorneys, the professionals being like, I
Speaker 3: can't do this. But to me is even worse insofar as it represents the Justice Department being used
Speaker 4: as not a shield, not protecting someone, but as a sword.
Both are terrifying. And
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): especially to...
One
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): like myself, a former prosecutor, U.S. attorney and attorney general for the state
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): of Connecticut for 20 years, an investigation, a prosecution, charges, an indictment can ruin lives. And the weaponization of justice smacks of Stalinist Russia, as Stalin's chief of his secret police said, show me the man and I'll show you the crime. Right. That's the way...
The
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): so-called justice
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): system operated in that autocracy. We are facing the same terrifying weaponization of justice here. I
know
Speaker 7: that you've written to the acting U.S. attorney for D.C., Ed Martin, who seems to
Speaker 8: be quite a character about some of what he's said. And he is only acting. Firstly, I think that some of these are impeachable offenses from officers
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): in the United States. We'll see what happens. I don't have much trust in the current Republican Congress.
Okay.
Speaker 10: You met your part. I think Roger Wicker, was he in a meeting with you today? He was. OK,
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): so Roger Wicker, who's the chair of the Armed Services Committee, Mississippi
Speaker 2: senator, he posted this picture. It was that saying that the deal is a huge step forward in securing mutual prosperity and peace for Americans and Ukrainians. It was a picture of him.
Speaker 2: He then deleted that post afterwards. What was the bipartisan meeting like?
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): The bipartisan meeting was extremely positive. We were on one side, he on the other, 10 of us, bipartisan.
He
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): was hailed
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): as a hero. Zelensky was ready willing able to sign that agreement and what was most striking Chris is the recognition that we have a mutual and common interest with Ukraine defending democracy
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): Putin will keep going against other democracies if he's not stopped in Ukraine and this mineral deal I happen to
differ with
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): the underlying premise that Ukraine should be paying America
and
We
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): should be thanking Ukraine, and we should be helping it without demanding an exploitive deal
Speaker 11 (lower-pitched voice): in this way. But there was support for the deal, and Zelensky clearly was ready, willing, and able to sign it. I
want
Speaker 12: to play what Senator
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): Lindsey Graham was
saying.
I think it
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): was at Munich. Were you at Munich? Did you go to Munich? So Munich's the big security conference, a bunch of U.S. senators go. I believe this original sound is from Munich, February 14th. I think
Speaker 14: that's right. This is him talking about Zelensky just two weeks ago and then talking about what happened today in the Oval Office.
Speaker 15: Take a listen. I
want to tell you
Speaker 16: and your people, you're the ally I've been hoping for all my life. Not one American has
Speaker 17: died defending Ukraine. You've taken our weapons and you've kicked their ass.
Speaker 17: And I'm very proud to have you as our ally. So what I
Speaker 18: think, complete, utter disaster. What I saw in the Oval Office was disrespectful. And I don't know if we can ever do business with Zelensky again. He either needs to resign and send somebody over that we can do business with, or he needs to change. How do you take this guy seriously?
Lindsey
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): Graham was right two weeks ago. I was in the room in Munich when he said that. And by the way, Lindsey Graham and I have traveled to Ukraine. I've been there
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): six times. And every time I've been there, Zelensky has exemplified the courage and strength of his people beginning right after
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): the invasion when they pushed the Russians back, belittling and demeaning
a
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): hero, he is really a hero, and he'll be more
of
Speaker 14: a hero now in Ukraine. - Well, what do you, I mean, look, there's probably 80 US senators, I would say, probably 80 to 85, that
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): would, in a, you know, secret ballot, basically support Zelensky, support US weapons, support security guarantees, wanna give them the strongest hand possible in any negotiations. That's not the position of the president
of the United
Speaker 9 (lower-pitched voice): States and the leader of the Republican
Party.
He
Speaker 3: wants to give part of Ukraine to Putin. He likes Putin. He doesn't like Ukraine and Zelensky. He likes the authoritarian model. He doesn't like democracies. I'm done asking,
Speaker 19: like, when Republican senators
are going to
Speaker 19: speak up. They're not going to, right? So now what happens?
Well,
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): first, you're absolutely right. There's a through line here. Trump's sycophancy to Putin, whether Helsinki or today, and the Republican sycophancy to
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): Trump.
But
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): what we
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): need to do is mobilize the American people who truly believe in Zelensky. It's one thing to be looking
Speaker 5 (lower-pitched voice): for gratitude. It's another to be demanding groveling, which is what they did today. And it was a pathetic ambush. I think a mugging, a bait and switch. They invited Zelensky to come. He was ready to sign this agreement, which favors the United States. And they, in effect,
ambushed
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): him. So I think we need
a mutuality
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): of interest to be recognized here. Senator Richard Blumenthal, Connecticut, thank you for your time tonight. Appreciate it. Thank you.